Register of the Soiuz russkikh shofferov Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Soiuz russkikh shofferov records,
1926-1943
2000C42
Soiuz russkikh shofferov (France)
1 microfilm reel 0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence and clippings, relating to the Russian émigré community and to labor conditions in France.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Administrative History
Russian taxicab drivers' union in France.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists mainly of clippings, along with some leaflets and a small amount of internal documentation of the Union of Russian Taxi-Drivers in Paris in the late 1920s-early 1930s. The Union, whose membership at one point numbered in the thousands, was a potent labor group that participated actively in the strike of 1934.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russians--France.; Labor unions--France.; Taxicab drivers--France.; France.; Russia.
Series Description
- Soiuz russkikh shofferov, 1926-1943. (Box 1)
  Records, including clipping files, broadsides and correspondence, arranged by physical form, and chronologically within
Container List
- SOIUZ RUSSKIKH SHOFFEROV, 1926-1943 (Box 1)
  - Clippings.
    Includes broadsides pasted onto sheets along with clippings
    - 1926-1928 (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1929-1930 (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1931 (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1934. (Folder 1: 5)
      Includes file on the strike of February 1934 as well as broadsides, internal memoranda, and reports on the strike
    - 1935-1940 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1943. (Folder 1: 7)
    Includes circulars
  - Miscellany, 1932-1933. (Folder 1: 8)
    Clippings on Federatsiia russkikh professional'nykh organizatsii, Soiuz russkikh sester miloserdiia and other émigré organizations, as well as on French immigration policy